Guide to the Derrick A. Bell, Jr. Papers MC.138
New York University Archives
- PUBLICATIONS AND LAW CASES (Boxes 110-119)(See boxes 118 and 119 for works by Bell)
  - Journals
    - Freedomways -Vol. 7, No 2-4, Spring, Summer, Fall 1967 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 8, No 1-3, Winter, Spring, Summer 1968 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 9, No 1-2, 4, Winter, Spring, 4th Quarter 1969 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 10, No 1-4, 1st-4th Quarters, 1970 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 11, No 1-4, 1971 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 12, No 1-3, 1972 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 13, No 1, 3-4, 1973 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 14, No 1-4, 1974 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 15, No 1-4, 1975 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 16, No 1-4, 1976 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 17, No 1-3, 1977 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 18, No 1-4, 1978 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 19, No 2, 4, 1979 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol 20, No 3, 4, 1980 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 21, No 1-4, 1981 (Box 115)
    - Freedomways -Vol. 22, No 2,3 1982 (Box 115)
  - Misc. Journals (Journals, publications from conferences, Law Reviews)
    Barcode: 31142042277106
    - ABA Journal Sept 1, 1987 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Autumn 1972 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Summer 1974 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Winter 1974/75 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Summer 1975 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Autumn 1975 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Winter 1975/76 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Autumn 1977 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Winter 1977/78 (Box 116)
    - The American Scholar Autumn 1978 (Box 116)
    - Annual Judicial Conference, May 13, 1965 (Box 116)
    - The Black Church Quarterly, 1972 (Box 116)
    - Black Issues in Higher Education Vol 6, No 18, Nov 23, 1989 (Box 116)
    - The Black Law Journal, 1971-1975 -Vol. 1, No. 1-3 (Box 116)
    - The Black Law Journal, 1971-1975 -Vol.2, No. 1, 3 (Box 116)
    - The Black Law Journal, 1971-1975 -Vol. 3, No. 2 and 3 (Box 116)
    - The Black Law Journal, 1971-1975 -Vol. 4, No. 1-3 (Box 116)
    - Black World Sept. 1971 (Box 116)
    - Black World Mar 1972 (Box 116)
    - Black World Apr 1974 (Box 116)
    - The Case Against Capital Punishment, The Washington Research Project, 1971 (Box 116)
    - Case and Comment Vol 68, No 6, Nov-Dec. 1963 (Box 116)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, -Fall 1973 (Box 116)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, -Summer, Fall, Winter/Spring 1974 (Box 116)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, -Fall, Winter, Spring 1975 (Box 116)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, -April/May, Aug/Sept, Oct/Nov 1976 (Box 116)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, -Dec (1976)/Jan, Feb/March, May/June, July/Aug 1977 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 1, No. 2,3 1968 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 2, No. 1-4 1969 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 3, No. 1-2 1970 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 4, No. 1-4 1971 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 5, No. 1 1972 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 6, No. 2 Summer 1973 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 7, No. 1 1974 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 8, No. 4 1976 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 9, No. 2 and 4 1977 (Box 116)
    - Civil Rights Digest -Vol. 10, No. 2 and 3 1978 (Box 116)
    - The Crisis Nov. 1962 (Box 116)
    - The Crisis Aug/Sept 1963 (Box 116)
    - The Crisis Jan. 1969 (Box 116)
    - Daedalus, Fall 1975, Fall 1976, Summer and Winter 1977, 1975-1977 (Box 117)
      Barcode: 31142042277114
    - The Education Digest, May, Sept and Nov. 1979 (Box 117)
    - Equal Educational Opportunities in the Cities, Report of The Hartford Conference March 1967 (Box 117)
    - Escape to Freedom by Vivian R. Johnson, 1974 (Box 117)
    - First World Vol. 1, No. 1-3, Jan.-June 1977 (Box 117)
    - First World Vol. 2, No. 1 Spring 1978 (Bell article within "The Curse of Brown on Black") (Box 117)
    - First World Vol 2, No 2 1979 (Bell article within "The Pest-Bakke Era: Do Blacks Have it Made in America?") (Box 117)
    - Harvard Journal on Legislation, April 1976 (Box 117)
    - Harvard Law Review, Vol. 90 No. 3-5, March-Feb 1977 (Box 117)
    - Inequality in Education Numbers. 8, 9, 12-17 (1974) (Box 117)
    - Integrateduction May-June, 1978 (Box 117)
    - The Journal of Negro History Vol. 40, No. 3, July 1955 (Box 117)
    - The Lincoln Review Vol. 2, No. 2, Summer 1981 (Box 117)
    - Michigan Law Review (bound) excerpted book review from Vol 86, No 6, May 1988 of "The NAACP's Legal Strategy Against Segregated Education" by Robert L. Carter (Box 117)
    - Negro Digest May 1963, Feb. 1969, 1963-1969 (Box 117)
    - Obsidian Vol. 2, No. 3, Winter 1976 (Box 117)
    - Obsidian Vol 3, No. 1, 2 Spring and Summer 1977 (Box 117)
    - Obsidian Vol 4, No 2, Summer 1978 (Box 117)
    - Pacific Historical Review Vol 39, No 3, Aug. 1970 (Box 117)
    - Partisan Review Winter 1959 (Box 117)
    - Philosophy and Public Affairs Vol 5, No. 2, Winter 1976 (Box 117)
    - Phylon March and June 1975 (Box 117)
    - The Public Interest No. 32, 1973 (Box 117)
    - The Public Interest No. 34, 1974 (Box 117)
    - The Public Interest No. 43, 1976 (Box 117)
    - The Public Interest No. 47 and 48, 1977 (Box 117)
    - The Public Interest No. 54, 1979 (Box 117)
    - The St. Louis Story: A Study of Desegregation by Bonita H. Valien, 1956 (Box 117)
    - UMOJA Vol. 2, No 3, Fall 1978 (Box 117)
    - The Yale Journal of Law and Liberation Vol 1, No. 1, Fall 1989 (Box 117)
  - Derrick Bell Published articles in Journals 1956-1993 (bound and un-bound)
    - Published articles, 1956-1957 (Box 118)
      Barcode:31142042277122
      -University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 17, No. 3, Spring 1956
      -University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 18, No. 2, Winter 1957
      -University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 18, No. 3, Spring 1957 (3)
      -University of Pittsburgh Law Review, Vol. 18, No. 4, Summer 1957
    - Published Articles, 1968-1974 (Box 118)
      - "The Western Center on Law and Poverty," from The LA Bar Bulletin, Oct. 1968 (3)
      -Univ. Of Toledo Law Review, Vol. 1970, No. 2&3, "Black Students in White Law Schools: The Ordeal and the Opportunity" (2)
      - "Black Students in White Law Schools: The Ordeal and the Opportunity" from Univ. Of Toledo Law Review, Vol. 1970 (paper)
      - "In Defense of Minority Admissions Programs: A Response to Professor Graglia," from UPenn Law Review, Dec. 1970 (3)
      -University of Pennsylvania Law Review, Vol. 119, No. 2, Dec. 1970, "In Defense of Minority Admissions Programs: A Response to Professor Graglia"
      - "School Litigation Strategies for the 1970's: New Phases in the Continuing Quest for Quality Schools," from
      - Book Review "Horowitz & Karst: Law, Lawyers & Social Change: Cases & Materials on the Abolition of Slavery, Racial Segregation & Inequality of Educational Opportunity" from UCLA Law Review, Feb.. 1971 (3)
      -Harvard Law School Bulletin, Vol 22, No. 3, Feb. 1971
      -National Policy Conference on Education for Blacks Proceedings, March 29-April 1, 1971, Washington, D.C.
      - "Black Faith in a Racist Land," from Howard Law Journal, Vol 17, No. 2, 1972 (3)
      -Inequality in Education, No. 11, March 1972, "Integration: A No Win Policy for Blacks?"
      -Harvard Law School Bulletin, Vol 23, No. 5, June 1972, "Integration: A No Win Policy for Blacks?" (3)
      -Criminal Law Bulletin, Vol. 9, No. 1 Book Review of: Race, Crime & Justice, 1972 (3)
      -Annual Orientation Program for Black Law Students, Sept 8, 1973, "Law School Exams & Minority-Group Students: The Problem & Some Suggested Solutions"
      -Freedomways, Vol 13, No. 4, 1973, "NAACP: Faith and Opportunity" (2)
      - "Racism in American Courts: Cause for Black Disruption or Despair?" from California Law Review, Jan 1973 (3)
      -California Law Review, Vol. 61, No. 1 Jan 1973 "Racism in American Courts: Cause for Black Disruption or Despair?" (2)
      -The Road Ahead, 1973 (NAACP) "Remedies for Employment Discrimination"
      - Book Review of The Case for Black Reparations by Prof. Boris I. Bittker, from Harvard Civil Rights - Civil
      - "The Real Cost of Racial Equality" from Civil Liberties Review, Survey, Summer 1974 (3)
    - Published Articles, 1975-1976 (Box 118)
      -Law and Contemporary Problems, Vol. 39, No. 1, Winter 1975, "Waiting on the Promise of Brown"
      -Law and Contemporary Problems, Vol. 39, No. 2, Spring 1975, "Waiting on the Promise of Brown" (3)
      - "Waiting on the Promise of Brown" from Law and Contemporary Problems, Spring 1975 (3)
      -Journal of Law & Education, Vol. 4, No. 1, Jan 1975, "A Special Commentary on the Detroit Met Desegregation Decision" (3)
      -N. Carolina Central Law Journal, Vol. 7, No 1, Fall 1975 "The Burden of Brown on Blacks: History-Based Observations on a Landmark Decision" (2)
      - "The Burden of Brown on Blacks: History-Based Observations on a Landmark Decision," from N. Carolina
      -Emory Law Journal, Vol 25, No. 4, Fall 1976, "Book Review: "Affirmation Discrimination: Ethnic Inequality & Public Policy" by Nathan Glazer
      -The Yale Law Journal, Vol 85 No. 4, March 1976 "Serving Two Masters: Integration Ideals & Client Interests in School Desegregation Litigation" (2)
      -Notre Dame Lawyer, Vol 52, No. 1, Oct. 1976, "Racial Remediation: An Historical Perspective on Current Conditions"
      - Book Review: "Justice Accused: Antislavery and the Judicial Process," from Columbia Law Review, March 1976 (3)
      - "Is Brown obsolete? Yes!" from Integrateducation, May-June, 1976
    - Published Articles, 1977-1978 (Box 118)
      Barcode: 31142042277122
      -Loyola University of Chicago Law Journal, Vol 8, No 4, Summer 1977, "Fair Employment Practices Symposium"
      -Southern University Law Review, Vol. 4, No. 1, Fall 1977, "Graglia: Disaster by Decree"
      - "The Legacy of W.E.B. Du Bois: A Rational Model for Achieving Public School Equity for America's Black Children," from Creighton Law Review, Dec 1977
      -Freedomways, Vol. 17, No. 1, 1977 "School Desegregation"
      -Business and Society Review, No. 22 Summer 1977, "A Civil Rights Suit Against A Law First"
      -Theory Into Practice, Vol 17, No 1, Feb 1978
      -Theory Into Practice, Vol 17, No 2, April 1978, "The Community Role in the Education of Poor, Black Children"
      -Juris Doctor, April 1978, "Inside Chicago: Conformity and Social Change"
      -First World, Vol 2, No 1, Spring 1978"The Curse of Brown on Black"
      -Clearinghouse for Civil Rights Research, Vol 6, No 1-2, Autumn-Winter 1978
      -Washington Law Review, "Lecture Series, The Referendum: Democracy's Barrier to Racial Equality"
      -The Journal of Negro History, Vol 63, No. 3, July 1978
      -Phi Kappa Phi Journal, Winter 1978, "The High Price of Non-Representation"
    - Published Articles, 1979-1980 (Box 118)
      -Change, Oct. 1979, "The Politics of Desegregation"
      -The Black Scholar, Vol 11, No. 1, Sept/Oct 1979, "Learning from the Brown Experience"
      -Emory Law Journal, Vol 28, No 4, Fall 1979, "Black Colleges & the Desegregation Dilemma"
      -California Law Review, Vol 67, No 1, Jan 1979, "Bakke, Minority Admissions, and the Usual Prince of Racial Remedies"
      - "Bakke, Minority Admissions, and the Usual Prince of Racial Remedies" from California Law Review, Vol 67, No 1, Jan 1979
      -Harvard Civil Rights Civil Liberties Law Review, Vol 14, No 1, Spring 1979, "Introduction: Awakening After Bakke"
      -Legal Analysis, No. 3, Oct. 1979, "A Gift of Time"
      -Oregon Law Review, Vol 59, No 2 & 3, 1980 "Humanity in Legal Education" (paper 2, 1 Bound)
      - "Brown v. Board of Education & the Interest-Convergence Dilemma," from The Harvard Law Review, Jan 1980 (3)
    - Published Articles, 1981-1985 (Box 119)
      Barcode: 31142042277163
      -The Education Digest, Feb 1981, "Redefining Racial Integration for Effectiveness" (2)
      - UConn Commencement Address, May 23, 1981, "Involuntary Career Challenges & The Equality Possibility" (3)
      -Michigan Law Review, 1981, Book Review " Britain, Blacks, and Busing" (3)
      - "Private Clubs & Public Judges: A Nonsubstantive Debate About Symbols," from Texas Law Review, April 1981 (3)
      -Alabama Law Review, Vol 32, No 2, Winter 1981, "The Dialectives of School Desegregation" (3)
      -The Yale Law Journal, Vol 90, No 8 July 1981 Book review of Bell Book Race, Racism and American Law (3)
      -The Yale Law Journal, Vol. 91, No. 4, March 1982, "Civil Rights Lawyers on the Bench BASS: Unlikely Heroes" (3)
      -Harvard Civil Rights Civil Liberties Law Review, Vol 16, No. 3, Winter 1982, Bell Reviews "Preferential Affirmative Action" by Daniel C. Maguire. (paper & 3 bound)
      -Oregon Law Review, Vol 61, No 2, 1982, "Foreword" (3)
      -Journal of Law & Education April 1982 Book review of Bell book Shades of Brown: New Perspectives on School Desegregation
      - The 1983 James McCormick Mitchell Lecture, Bell Lecture "A Hurdle Too High: Class-based Roadblocks to Racial Remediation" (paper)
      - The 1983 James McCormick Mitchell Lecture, Bell Lecture "A Hurdle Too High: Class-based Roadblocks to Racial Remediation" from Buffalo Law Review 1984
      - "Time for the Teachers: Putting Educators Back Into the Brown Remedy" from Journal of Negro Education, 1983 (2)
      -Phi Delta Kappan, April 1983, "Learning from our Loses: Is School Desegregation Still Feasible in the 1980s?" (3)
      -U.C. Davis Law Review, Vol 17, No 2, Winter 1984, "A Holiday for Dr. King: The Significance of Symbols in the Black Freedom Struggle"
      -Harvard Civil Rights Civil Liberties Law Review, Vol 19, No 2, Summer 1984, "A Tragedy of Timing"
      -Suffolk University Law Review, Vol. 18, No 3, Fall 1984, "An American Fairy Tale: The Income-Related Neutralization of Race Law Precedent"
      -Oregon Law Review, Vol 63, No. 4, 1984, "Introduction" (3)
      - The Supreme Court 1984 Term, "Foreword: The Civil Rights Chronicles" from Harvard Law Review, Nov 1985 (3)
      -Harvard Law Review, Nov 1985 The Supreme Court 1984 Term, "Foreword: The Civil Rights Chronicles"
      -Centerboard: The Journal of the Center for Human Relations Studies, Vol3, No 1, Spring 1985, "Is American Racism Economics by Another Name?"
    - Published Articles, 1986-1993 (Box 119)
      - "The Dilemma of the Responsible Law Reform Lawyer in the Post-Free Enterprise Era," from Law & Inequality: A Journal of Theory & Practice, July 1986 (3)
      -University of San Francisco Law Review, Vol 20, No 3, Spring 1986, "Strangers in Academic Paradise: Law Teachers of Color in Still White Schools" (3)
      -Nova Law Journal, Vol 10, No 2, Winter 1986, "Application of the 'Tipping Point' Principle to Law Faculty Hiring Policies" (3)
      -The Harvard Blackletter Journal, Spring 1986, "The Civil Rights Chronicles Revisited: Comments & Intro" (3)
      - "Equal Opportunity in Higher Education & the Black Public College: The Era of Separate But Equal," Forward by D. Bell from Minnesota Law Review, Oct. 1987 (3)
      -Minnesota Law Review, Vol 72, No 1, Oct. 1987 "Foreword"
      -The Georgetown Law Journal, Vol 76, No 1, Oct 1987, "Law, Litigation, & the Search for the Promised Land" (3)
      -Harvard Law Bulletin, Autumn 1987, Peggy Davis Book review of "And We are not Saved" (2)
      -Villanova Law Review, Vol 33, No 5, 1988, "White Superiority in AmericaL Its Legal Legacy, Its Economic Costs
      -The Yale Law Journal, Vol 97, No 8, July 1988, "The Republician Revival & Racial Politics"
      - Book Review by Preeta D. Bansal on Bell's "And we are not Saved: The Elusive Quest for Racial Justice" from Harvard Law Review, Feb. 1988 (3)
      - Book Review by Maureen P. Taylor on Bell's "And we are not Saved: The Elusive Quest for Racial Justice" from Michigan Law Review, May 1988 (paper)
      -National Black Law Journal, Vol 10, No 3, 1988 Book Review of Bell's "And we are not Saved" (paper)
      -NY Law School, Journal of Human Rights, Vol 5, Part 2, Spring 1988, "The Constitution at 200: Reflections on the Past-Implications for the Future" (3)
      -Michigan Law Review, Vol 87, No 8, Aug 1989, "The Final Report: Harvard's Affirmative Action Allegory"
      -The Harvard Blackletter Journal, Spring 1989, "An Epistolary Exploration for a Thurgood Marshall Biography" (paper)
      -George Washington Law Review, Vol 57, No 6, Aug 1989, "Xerces & the Affirmative Action Mystique"
      -UCLA Law Review, Vol 37, No 6, 1990, "Racial Reflections: Dialogues in the Direction of Liberation"
      -The Yale Journal of Law & Liberation from 1990 Scholarship ball of Mass Black Lawyers Assoc, "The Law of Racial Standing" (3)
      - "A Student Challenge to the Old Guard" from Student Lawyer Sept. 1990 (article discusses Bell)
      -The Black Scholar, Vol 22, No 1 & 2, "A Radical Double Agent" (2)
      - "Political Reality Testing: 1993" from Fordham Law Review Vol. 61, No 5, April 1993 (3)
- SERIES IV: COURSE MATERIALS (Accession 03-008)
  - Student Papers RESTRICTED, 1999-2002 (Box 120)
    Barcode: 31142042266604
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE (Accessions 01-013, 02-014, 05-003, 05-005 & 06-011)
  - October, 1992 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042266612
  - November, 1992 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - December, 1992 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - January, 1993 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - January, 1993 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - June, 1993 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - May, 1994 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - January, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - February, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - March, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - April, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - May, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - June, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 13)
  - July, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 14)
  - August, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 15)
  - September, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 16)
  - October, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 17)
  - November, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 18)
  - December, 1995 (Box 121, Folder 19)
  - January, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 20)
  - February, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 21)
  - March, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 22)
  - April, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 22)
  - May, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 23)
  - June, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 24)
  - July, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 25)
  - September, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 27)
  - October, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 28)
  - November, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 29)
  - December, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 30)
  - January, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 31)
  - February, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 32)
  - Spring, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 33)
  - Summer, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 34)
  - Fall, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 35)
  - Spring, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 36)
  - Summer, Fall, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 37)
  - January, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042266620
  - February, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - March, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - April, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - May, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - June, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - July, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - August, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - September, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - October, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - November, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - December, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - Messages, 1998-2000 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042266638
  - January, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - February, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - March, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - April, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - May, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - June, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - July, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - August, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - September, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 10)
  - October, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 11)
  - November, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 12-13)
  - December, 2000 (Box 123, Folder 14)
  - January, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042266646
  - February, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - March, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - April, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - May, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - June, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - July, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - August, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - September, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - October, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - November, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 11)
  - December, 2001 (Box 124, Folder 12)
  - Messages, 2000-2002 (Box 124, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 124, Folder 14)
  - January, 2004 (Box 124, Folder 15)
  - February, 2004 (Box 124, Folder 16)
  - March, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042266653
  - April, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - May, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - June, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - July, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - August, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - September, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - October, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - November, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 9)
  - December, 2004 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Old Correspondence, 1971-1984 (Box 125, Folder 11)
- SERIES II: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (Accessions 01-013, 02-014, 05-003 & 06-011)
  - AALS - San Francisco, Jan 2000 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042262181
  - Trinity University, Jan 2000 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - University of Virginia, Jan 2000 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Auction, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - College of William and Mary, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Martin Luther King Library, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Howard Lecture, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Vanderbilt University, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Law Professors Luncheon, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Missouri Historical Society, Feb 2000 (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Professor Sherrilyn Ifill, Mar 2000 (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Marywood College, Mar 2000 (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Univ. of Penn BLSA Dinner, Mar 2000 (Box 126, Folder 13)
  - Maya Angelou Public Charter School, Mar 2000 (Box 126, Folder 14)
  - SUNY Albany, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 15)
  - Colgate University, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 16)
  - NYU 1999-2000 Moot Court, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 17)
  - A Morning on the Millenium, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 18)
  - Northeast People of Color Conference, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 19)
  - North Orleans AERA Conference, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 20)
  - New Orleans Public Library, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 21)
  - National Association of Black Telecommunications, Apr 2000 (Box 126, Folder 22)
  - Samuel Konefsky Memorial Lecture, May 2000 (Box 126, Folder 23)
  - Pre-Convocation Dinner and Performance, May 2000 (Box 126, Folder 24)
  - Multicultural Resource Center, Jun 2000 (Box 126, Folder 25)
  - Jack and Jill Regional Teen Conference, Jun 2000 (Box 126, Folder 26)
  - Ragina Gupta Wedding, Aug 2000 (Box 126, Folder 27)
  - Yale, Sep 2000 (Box 126, Folder 28)
  - Pam Newkirk Book Reception, Sep 2000 (Box 126, Folder 29)
  - Univ. of Pittsburgh Black Alumni, Sep 2000 (Box 126, Folder 30)
  - Gayle Winjen Wedding, Sep 2000 (Box 126, Folder 31)
  - Columbia University (Revson Fellows Program), Sep 2000 (Box 126, Folder 32)
  - Harvard Law School Black Alumni, Sep2000 (Box 126, Folder 33)
  - Just the Beginning Foundation, Sep 2000-Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 34)
  - University of Maryland, Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 35)
  - Hurston/Wright, Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 36)
  - Martia Golden, Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 37)
  - All Souls Church, Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 38)
  - "Please Do Not Erase!" Manuscript, Oct 2000 (Box 126, Folder 39)
  - Derrick Bell Lecture, Nov 2000 (Box 126, Folder 40)
  - "Teaching Large Classes", Nov 2000 (Box 126, Folder 41)
  - Review of David Troutt, Nov 2000 (Box 126, Folder 42)
  - Woodstock Library Forum, Nov 2000 (Box 126, Folder 43)
  - Manhattan Country School, Dec 2000 (Box 126, Folder 44)
  - 2000 Education Leadership Summit, Dec 2000 (Box 126, Folder 45)
  - Meet the Author Dinner, Dec 2000 (Box 126, Folder 46)
  - Installation Sermon for Dr. Thomas Davis, undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
    Barcode: 31142042262199
  - Meeting in San Francisco, Jan 2001 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - AALS Workshop, Jan 2001 (Box 127, Folder 3)